# 本人今天做一个
# （蔬菜汁炖豆腐）
# （二伯独创 超级健康）
Today, I'm gonna cook
(Veggie and Tofu Stew)
(Er Bai's private healthy recipe)
# 正经八百的养生豆腐
# （蔬菜汁炖豆腐）
# （二伯独创 超级健康）
an absolutely healthy tofu dish
(Veggie and Tofu Stew)
(Er Bai's private healthy recipe)
# 养生豆腐？
Healthy tofu dish?
# 这肉片有点多了
# （五花肉切片）
That's a bit too much meat
(Slice the pork belly)
# 有多少搁多少
# （五花肉切片）
I'm just using all that I have
(Slice the pork belly)
# 我爱吃肉
# （五花肉切片）
I'm a meat lover
(Slice the pork belly)
# 你看 一个大料
Look, a star anise
# 葱一段 姜两片 蒜四粒
A chunk of scallion, two slices of ginger, four cloves of garlic
# 现在开始 砂锅 开火
Now start. Clay pot set, fire on
# 你看 行啦
That's it!
# 操作方法简单
Very simple process
# 很简单
Very simple
# 你别说 网友学你这菜很容易
You know what, the audience can learn it easily
# 一看就会啊
Just watch and learn
# 倒油
Oil in
# 可以啦
Alright
# 肉和大料同时下
Pork and star anise in, at the same time
# 网友们看清楚啊
Watch it closely my friends
# 肉的煸炒啊
Dry stir fry the pork
# 差不多了啊
Good enough
# 放姜葱蒜
Ginger, scallion and garlic in
# 这香味出来了啊
The aroma has come out
# 你看看这芹菜可不少啊
That's a lot of celery
# 砂锅其实保持温度是最好的
Clay pots are the best at holding the heat
# 你看他切块这么大
You see, he's chopping big chunks
# 我明白是什么意思了
I know what that means
# 不是二哥刀工不好
It's not that you have poor knife skill
# 是二伯讲究食材营养素保持的好
It's because Er Bai wants to preserve the nutrients
# 小葱头 # 视频里看着像个洋葱，请核对
Onion
# 行了啊
Alright
# 花雕酒
Huadiao wine
# 你看见没有 从边上一呲
Look at it! Let it sizzle at the edge
# 这香味就出来了
The aroma comes out immediately
# 糖啊 糖一点就好
Sugar. Just a bit of sugar
# 来点胡椒粉
Some pepper powder
# 增增香
Enhance the aroma
# 这就行啦
Good
# 然后就酱油了
Then soy sauce
# 酱油得出香味啊
We gotta bring out the aroma of the soy sauce
# 今天炖的是红色豆腐
We'll make a red tofu stew today
# - 半瓶酱油下去啦 - 没有
- That's half a bottle in there
- That is not
# 最后你看看 来点香菜
Finally some cilantro
# 水 放进去
Water in
# - 一块块码呢 - 码进去
- You're stacking them chunk by chunk
- Stack them in
# 老抽
Dark soy sauce
# 这炖多久呢？
Hong long do we stew?
# 炖啊 二十分钟
For like 20 minutes
# 这个家伙得大一点
We need a big pot
# 要使那大锅炖好
It's best to stew with a bit pot
# 三叔看你家大砂锅没有 门背后头
San Shu, check behind your door. Is your big clay pot there?
# - 没有啦 - 没啦 - 就这个吧
- Nope
- No?
- Just use this one
# 颜色红亮啊 红汤
Red and shinny
# 这个豆腐调好了味儿就可以炖
We can start stewing the tofu after seasoning
# 炖到什么程度呢
Stew to what degree?
# 里边出了蜂窝
When there's a honeycomb pattern
# 蔬菜营养汁全部打进去
So all the nutrients of the veggies are absorbed
# 所以说这锅菜你看似简单
So you know, this dish looks very simple
# 是所有的菜里边营养素最丰富的
But it's actually the richest in nutrients
# 一会 它一开锅
Just in a while, when we open the lid
# 我不用说别的
I don't need to say anything
# 你们俩尝尝这汤你们俩就明白
As soon as you take a sip of the soup
# 真正这个菜的内涵
You'll understand the essence of this dish
# 就是说到这咱们俩还没明白呢？
So you mean we haven't understood it so far?
# - 你尝尝这味儿 - 你尝尝这汤
- Have a taste
- Taste the soup
# 全是蔬菜的清香味
Full of the freshness of the veggies
# 甜鲜啊 是不是
Sweet and umami, isn't it?
# 蔬菜的甜 蔬菜的香味
Sweetness and flavor of the veggies
# 对对对 甜鲜
Yea yea yea. Sweet and umami
# 盖锅盖了 可以盖锅盖了
# （锅开后盖盖子 转小火煮二十分钟）
Put on the lid now
(Lid on after boiling. Simmer for 20 minutes)
# - 三叔给盖上 - 好 小火
# （以豆腐出现蜂窝状为准）
- Put on the lid, San Shu
- Alright, low heat
(Until the tofu develops a honeycomb pattern)
# 都好啦 松软松软
Done. Puffy and soft
# 关键是什么 这气味太舒服了
The key is, the aroma is so pleasant
# 满屋子蔬菜的香味
The room is full of the aroma of the veggies
# 起锅
Ready to serve
# 真烫 好吃
So hot! So tasty!
# 我发现一什么问题
I just realized something
# 您吃饭您还没有他美呢
You are the one eating, but he seems more joyful
# 他的心情美啊
He has such a joyful mood
# 大哥吃了我高兴
Brother enjoys it, I'm happy
# 我来一块
Let me try one
# 太快了
So fast!
# 都有蜂窝了 你看见没有
Looks like a honeycomb. See?
# 全是菜味儿
Full of the veggie flavors
# 豆腐改菜味儿了
Veggie flavored tofu
# 蔬菜那种香味全进去了
All the veggie flavors are in
# 太棒了
Excellent!
# import ending.sbv 0:03:43.220